Guide to the Robert Mearns Yerkes Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Information on Yerkes' politics is located in two sections of Series II - Causes and Organizations. Information about Yerkes' institutional affiliations and teaching can also be found in Series II. See the files under the headings for Harvard University, Johns Hopkins University, University of Minnesota, Teaching, Ursinus College, and Yale University. The University of Minnesota and Johns Hopkins University files are particularly interesting. By 1916, Yerkes, still an assistant professor, felt that his career at Harvard was at a standstill and he began searching for a new position. The University of Minnesota in the spring of 1916, which was in the process of separating psychology from philosophy, offered Yerkes the position of chair of the new psychology department together with the post of director of the psychological laboratory at the rank of full professor. Yerkes declined the offer, but it was renewed in 1917 and he accepted. The war, however, intervened and afterwards Yerkes became employed by the National Research Council. He resigned a position that he never filled in March 1919. The next year he negotiated unsuccessfully with Johns Hopkins University in the hope of developing psychobiological and anthropoid research there. Not until 1924 did he find a university position that would allow him to pursue primate studies, negotiations found in Series I in the correspondence of James R. Angell and Roswell P. Angier.
Two other major subjects are covered in Series II. Correspondence, reports, and articles on psychology in World War II are found in Boxes 94-96. Information on the extensive publishing activities of Yerkes is located in the sections Periodicals, Publishers, Reprints and Reproducing, Research, and Works by Yerkes. What is found in Series II, however, is primarily correspondence about his research and publications, not copies of the publications. For copies of his publications, see Series IV, WRITINGS.
Series III, EXPERIMENTS, is contained in Boxes 114-120 of the Robert M. Yerkes Papers. It consists of notebooks of observations on chimpanzees and the gorilla Congo, notes on experiments with chimpanzees, and a laboratory log covering the period 1925-1942. These materials are housed in Boxes 114-117 and 120. A variety of other materials is found from the end of Box 117 through Box 119, including announcements for Yale's Institute of Psychology, pro-seminar syllabi, and several bound typescripts. One of the bound typescripts is The Biojonnismith, a publication "containing short tales for the juvenile mind," edited and produced by Yerkes, R. Myron Strong, Helen Makepeace, C.A. Holbrook, and Ada Watterson at Woods Hole in 1900-1901. The other bound typescripts date from the first decade of the twentieth century and consist of pseudonymous manuscripts written under the names C.J. Blix and Romby.
Series IV consists of WRITINGS and is divided into two sections. The first section, Books, is housed in Boxes 121-127 and the second section, Papers, is in Boxes 127-130. WRITINGS contain copies of books, articles, and reviews of Robert M. and Ada Watterson Yerkes, plus a handful of related materials by others. Books has copies of such major publications as The Dancing Mouse (1907), A Point Scale of Measuring Mental Ability (1915) with James W. Bridges and Rose S. Hardwick, Psychological Examining in the United States Arm (1921), Almost Human (1925), The Mind of a Gorilla (1926-1928), and The Great Apes (1929). Also included is John Dewey's Psychology, third revised edition 1893, about which Yerkes states, "this little books gave me my introduction to psychology as science," The Uses of the Past (1952) by Herbert J. Muller, and several other items. The section on Papers has nine bound volumes of articles and reviews by Robert M. Yerkes and Ada Watterson Yerkes published between 1899 and 1956, plus a binder containing publications too large to be included in the bound papers, publications about Yerkes including biographical memoirs, and items printed after his death. Each bound volume contains an index to all items included within the volume. A complete listing to all the publications of Robert M. and Ada Watterson Yerkes is found in Box 130, folder 2235.
The Robert M. Yerkes Papers contains fifteen boxes of photographs and these make up Series V. PHOTOGRAPHS. Boxes 131-136 house professional photographs and they consist primarily of albums of chimpanzee and gorilla pictures plus book illustrations and World War I photos. Personal photographs are contained in Boxes 137-145 and also largely consist of albums. Most of the pictures were taken by Ada Watterson Yerkes and Roberts Yerkes Blanshard, virtually all pictures are clearly identified, and the albums contain contents listings.
The final series, PERSONAL PAPERS, fills Boxes 146-177. The material is arranged under broad headings, the most important being Autobiographical, Biographical, Family, Family: Relatives, and Diaries.
The Autobiographical section, located in Box 146, folders 2311-2319, contains a typescript of Robert M. Yerkes "Testament," a document that is both an autobiography and a statement of his belief in the efficacy of science. A microfilm copy of the "Testament" is available as HM Film 133. The Biographical section, Boxes 146-157, contains biographical memoirs and obituaries, reminiscences, school memorabilia, college and graduate school materials, honorary degrees, address books, a report on the 1976 Yerkes Centennial Conference, and a variety of similar materials. Under the heading for Family, Boxes 159-165, one finds correspondence, biographical material, writings, research notes, and miscellanea on Ada Watterson Yerkes; correspondence of son David Norton Yerkes and his wife and daughter; letters of Robert M. Yerkes to his wife Ada, son David, and daughter Roberta; and correspondence of Roberta Watterson Yerkes Blanshard. Family: Relatives, Boxes 165-168, contains letters to and from Carrell, Diebitsch, Hughes, Krusen, Mearns, Norton, Watterson, and Yerkes relatives together with letters of members of the immediate family of Robert N. Yerkes, his parents Susanna Addis Carrell and Silas Marshall Yerkes and younger brothers Miles and William Augustus Yerkes. The final section, Diaries, is housed in Boxes 169-177. Robert M. Yerkes began keeping a diary in 1893, a practice he faithfully continued to 1906. The collection contains five diaries covering some of the years between 1908 and 1920 and a final series of diaries covering the period 1940-1954. In addition there are lists of and annotations for books read between 1891 and 1893, a daily record of his anthropoid research at the Abreu plantation in 1924, a log and notes from his 1929 European and African journey, five diaries of Ada Watterson Yerkes, a date book, and record of household accounts for the period 1905-1912.
Researchers can find information in Series VI on the research and professional interests of Professor Yerkes. Those interested in the subject of anthropoid research should examine family correspondence, particularly letters from Robert M. Yerkes to his wife, Boxes 163-164; letters to other family members; the "Testament," Box 146; writings and notes of Ada Watterson Yerkes, Box 161; and his 1924 notes taken at the plantation of Madame Rosalia Abreu, Box 172, folder 2666. Yerkes' World War I military experiences in psychological testing can likewise be traced through the "Testament," correspondence with his wife, and his 1917-1918 war journal, Box 171, folder 2663.
PERSONAL PAPERS contain a great deal of material documenting the educational growth of Robert M. Yerkes at West Chester State Normal School, Ursinus College, and Harvard University. The diaries of Yerkes, Boxes 169-170, are especially useful in this context. The documentation for his years at Ursinus College and Harvard University, Boxes 147-155, is particularly rich. Yerkes' Ursinus College years, 1893-1897, are represented by course grades, papers, notebooks, essays and exercises, exams, and a variety of printed materials. For further information on his devotion to Ursinus, see the small section for Ursinus College in Series II, Box 91, folders 1739-1742. The Harvard University material, 1897-1902, includes bills, grades, exams, fellowships, etc. plus an extensive collection of philosophy, psychology, and zoology notebooks and papers. The diaries and the Woods Hole files, Boxes 155-156, folders 2436-2344, provide a useful record of his early research activities.
The Real Estate section and correspondence in the Family sections have material on the Franklin, New Hampshire farm owned by Yerkes. Purchased in 1911, the farm served as a family retreat and site for early chimpanzee research. Additional information about the Franklin property is scattered throughout Series I. See, for example, the files for Walter B. Cannon, Burton E. Eames, Louisa Eyre, and Lee Russell.
The sections devoted to Family and Family: Relatives are housed in Boxes 159-168. They consist primarily of correspondence and all of it to, from, and about Yerkes and Watterson relatives, except for four folders of correspondence of Ada Watterson Yerkes with friends, one of whom, Elizabeth Cutter Morrow, was the mother of Anne Morrow Lindbergh. Although the collection contains a great deal of correspondence between Robert and Ada Yerkes, Boxes 159 and 163-164, few letters date from the period before their September 1905 marriage. Most of these letters were destroyed by the family.
The family correspondence and diaries, supplemented by the "Testament," give information about a wide variety of domestic topics. The letters between husband and wife reveal the deep feelings of love and respect they had for each other and also the sense that their marriage was a true partnership. Ada Watterson Yerkes authored or coauthored ten articles, four of which concerned primates, and also coauthored The Great Apes: A Study of Anthropoid Life (1929). Yerkes enjoyed warm relationships with his children, two brothers, many cousins, uncles and aunts, and his mother, who died of cancer in 1913, but he was not close to his father, Silas M. Yerkes. Father and son disagreed on the relative importance of education and farm work, a situation made more difficult by financial problems caused by a fire that destroyed the Yerkes farm in 1893. From these same sources researchers can also find useful material about farm life and rural conditions in Bucks County, Pennsylvania at the end of the nineteenth century and about youthful activities and college life. After retirement Yerkes became increasingly interested in family history and delighted in recalling the events of his youth, thus readers interested in these subjects should examine the "round robin" letters to his brothers Miles and William Augustus Yerkes in Boxes 167-168. See also Box 147, folders 2329-2334 for additional material on life in Bucks County in the late nineteenth century.
The final Oversize section contains a sound recording of vocalization of baby gorillas, a microfilm copy of correspondence between Yerkes and E.B. Titchener found at Cornell University, one trunk of World War I era psychological testing materials, and a roll of charts on psychological examining in World War I.
Those seeking additional background information on Robert M. Yerkes should consult his Testament, Box 146, folders 2311-2317 and Memoirs, Box 146, folder 2323. The biographical memoirs written by Edwin G. Boring for the Year Book of the American Philosophical Society ,1956 and Ernest R. Hilgard for the National Academy of Sciences in 1965 are particularly good. The latter essay has a twenty-four page biographical sketch, chronology, and bibliography of the publications of Robert M. Yerkes.
Biographical / Historical
Robert Mearns Yerkes was born on May 26, 1876 in Breadysville, Pennsylvania. He was one of the most eminent psychologists of his day, noted chiefly for his studies of primate behavior and his psychological testing in World War I. He died in New Haven, Connecticut on February 3, 1956. Yerkes graduated from Ursinus College in 1897, received a second A.B. from Harvard in 1898, and a Ph.D in psychology in 1902. He taught at Harvard University, 1902-1917; served in World War I, 1917-1919; worked at the National Research Council, 1919-1924; and was professor of psychology and psychobiology at Yale University, 1924-1944.
Chimpanzees -- Behavior; Emigration and immigration; Eugenics; Families; Gorilla -- Behavior; Intelligence levels; Intelligence tests; Primates -- Study and teaching; Psychobiology; Psychology -- Study and teaching; Sexology -- Research; World War, 1914-1918 -- Testing; Bucks County (Pa.); Franklin (N.H.); Orange Park (Fla.); Diaries; Photographs; Psychologists; Abreu, Rosalia; Adams, Donald Keith, 1902-1971; Akeley, Mary L. Jobe (Mary Lenore Jobe), 1878-1966; Allen, Edgar, 1892-1943; Angell, James Rowland, 1869-1949; Angier, Roswell Parker, 1874-1946; Benchley, Belle Jennings, 1882-; Bingham, Harold C. (Harold Clyde), 1888-1964; Bingham, Walter Van Dyke, 1880-1952; Boring, Edwin Garrigues, 1886-1968; Breed, Frederick S. (Frederick Stephen), 1876-; Brigham, Carl C. (Carl Campbell), 1890-1943; Britt, Steuart Henderson, 1907-1979; Burbridge, Benjamin, 1880-1936; Burnett, Charles T. (Charles Theodore), 1873-; Burtt, Harold E. (Harold Ernest), 1890-; Cannon, Walter B. (Walter Bradford), 1871-1945; Carmichael, Leonard, 1898-1973; Carpenter, C. Ray (Clarence Ray), 1905-1975; Cattell, James McKeen, 1860-1944; Cole, Lawrence Wooster, 1870-1946; Conklin, Edwin Grant, 1863-1952; Coolidge, Harold J. (Harold Jefferson), 1904-1985; Corner, George W. (George Washington), 1889-1981; Crawford, Meredith P. (Meredith Pullen), 1910-2002; Cushing, Harvey, 1869-1939; Dallenbach, Karl M., 1887-1971; Davenport, Charles Benedict, 1866-1944; Dodge, Raymond, 1871-1942; Doll, Edgar A. (Edgar Arnold), 1889-; Dunlap, Knight, 1875-1949; Elder, James Harlan, 1902-; Elliott, Richard Maurice, 1887-1969; Embree, Edwin R. (Edwin Rogers), 1883-1950; Eyre, Louisa, -1953; Fels, Samuel S. (Samuel Simeon), 1860-1950; Flexner, Abraham, 1866-1959; Flexner, Simon, 1863-1946; Flinn, Alfred D. (Alfred Douglas), 1869-1937; Fulton, John F. (John Farquhar), 1899-1960; Gellerman, Louis W.; Gould, Charles W. (Charles Winthrop), 1849-1931; Greenman, Milton J. (Milton Jay), 1866-1937; Gregg, Alan, 1890-1957; Haggerty, Melvin E. (Melvin Everett), 1875-1937; Hale, George Ellery, 1868-1938; Hamilton, G. V.; Harlow, Harry F. (Harry Frederick), 1905-1981; Hartman, Carl G. (Carl Gottfried), 1879-1968; Harwell, Edalee Orcutt; Haslerud, George Martin; Hayes, Cathy; Healy, William, 1869-1963; Herrick, C. Judson (Charles Judson), 1868-1960; Hilgard, Ernest R. (Ernest Ropiequet), 1904-2001; Hull, Clark Leonard, 1884-1952; Hunter, Walter S. (Walter Samuel), 1889-1954; Jacobsen, Carlyle Ferdinand, 1902-; Jennings, H. S. (Herbert Spencer), 1868-1947; Kellogg, W. N. (Winthrop Niles), 1898-1972; Kinsey, Alfred C. (Alfred Charles), 1894-1956; Köhler, Wolfgang, 1887-1967; La Rue, Daniel Wolford, 1878-1969; Ladygina-Kots, N. N. (Nadezhda Nikolaevna), 1890-1963; Langfeld, Herbert Sidney, 1879-1958; Lashley, Karl S. (Karl Spencer), 1890-1958; Lathrop, A. E. C. (Abbie E. C.), 1868-1918; Learned, William S. (William Setchel), 1876-1950; Lillie, Frank Rattray, 1870-1947; Louttit, C. M. (Chauncey McKinley), 1901-1956; May, Mark A. (Mark Arthur), 1891-1977; Meriam, Junius Lathrop, 1872-; Merriam, Charles Edward, 1874-1953; Merriam, John C. (John Campbell), 1869-1945; Meyer, Adolf, 1866-1950; Miles, Walter R. (Walter Richard), 1885-1978; Münsterberg, Hugo, 1863-1916; Murchison, Carl, 1887-1961; Nissen, Henry Wieghorst, 1901-1958; Pearl, Raymond, 1879-1940; Pressey, Sidney L. (Sidney Leavitt), 1888-1979; Rand, Herbert W. (Herbert Wilbur), 1872-1960; Riesen, Austin H. (Austin Herbert); Riopelle, A. J.; Ritter, William Emerson, 1856-1944; Schultz, Adolph H. (Adolph Hans), 1891-; Scripps, E. W. (Edward Willis), 1854-1926; Seashore, Carl E. (Carl Emil), 1866-1949; Southard, Elmer Ernest, 1876-1920; Spangler, Ralph H. (Ralph Huston), 1877-1962; Sparks, Richard D.; Spence, Kenneth W. (Kenneth Wartenbee), 1907-1967; Speranza, Gino Charles, 1872-1927; Spragg, S. D. S. (Sidney Durward Shirley); Strong, Reuben Myron, 1872-1964; Terman, Lewis M. (Lewis Madison), 1877-1956; Thorndike, Edward L. (Edward Lee), 1874-1949; Tinklepaugh, Otto Leif; Titchener, Edward Bradford, 1867-1927; Todd, T. Wingate (Thomas Wingate), 1885-1938; Tomilin, Michael I.; Van Kleeck, Mary, 1883-1972; Warren, Howard C. (Howard Crosby), 1867-1934; Washburn, Margaret Floy, 1871-1939; Watson, John B. (John Broadus), 1878-1958; Welch, William Henry, 1850-1934; Whiting, Charles Frederick, 1875-1972; Whitney, Leon F. (Leon Fradley), 1894-1973; Winternitz, M. C. (Milton C.), 1885-1959; Wissler, Clark, 1870-1947; Yerkes, Ada W. (Ada Watterson), 1873-1963; Yerkes, Robert M. (Robert Mearns), 1876-1956; Yoshioka, Joseph Geno, 1893-; Young, William C. (William Caldwell), 1899-1965; Zinn, Earl F.; Zuckerman, Solly, Baron, 1904-1993; Yerex family; Harvard University. Class of 1898; Harvard University. Dept. of Psychology; National Research Council (U.S.); Ursinus College. Class of 1897; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Department of Psychology; Yale University. Institute of Human Relations; Yerkes Laboratories of Primate Biology; Yerkes Laboratories of Primate Biology
- Professional Correspondence, 1898-1982; Series I; 22.25 linear feet (54 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I contains 54 boxes of alphabetically arranged correspondence files. All material is arranged in chronological order within each folder and individuals are given separate listings, provided the file contains six or more items to, from, or about that parson. The correspondence of those who appear one to five times is filed alphabetically with the first letter of the surname in "Letter" general files. Folders containing ten or more items to, from, or about a person are marked with an asterisk (*).
  PROFESSIONAL CORRESPONDENCE lists the names of 765 individuals, 457 of whom are represented by ten or more items. Included within the total are the names of seventy-nine men and women whose correspondence is found in later series.
  - "A" general, 1899-1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aberle, Sophie D. (*), 1945-1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ahreu, Pierre (*), 1925-1952 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  - Abreu, Rosalia (*), 1915-1930 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Abreu, (Mme. Henraux), 1940, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Abreu clippings, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Abreu notes, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Achilles, Paul S., 1943 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    General note
    See also: box 83, folders 1615-1625
  - Adams, Charles C., 1932-1942 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Adams, Comfort A., 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Adams, Donald K. (*), 1925-1956 (Box 1, Folder 14-17)
  - Agassiz, George R., 1915-1935 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Akeley, Carl F. (*), 1922-1927 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Akeley, Mary L. Jobe (*), 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Akeley, Mary L. Jobe, 1930-1956 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Allee, W.C. (*), 1938-1947 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Allen, Edgar (*), 1933-1943 (Box 2, Folder 23-24)
    See also: box 105, folders 1988-1990
  - Allport, Gordon W. (*), 1942-1946 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Alverdes, Friedrich, 1938-1947 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Amsden, George S. (*), 1901-1933 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Anderegg, G.A., 1905-1940 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Anderson, Benjamin M., 1921, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Anderson, John E. (*), 1917-1956 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Angell, James R. (*), 1906-1956 (Box 2, Folder 31-38)
    See also: box 56, folders 1068-1069 box 104, folders 1955-1956 box 106 folders 1995-1996
  - Angier, Roswell P. (*), 1902-1904 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    See also: box 57, folders 1094 box 102, folders 1923-1924 box 103, folders 1939-1940 box 104, folder 1961 box 105, folders 1976-1978
  - Angier, Roswell P., 1905-1946 (Box 3, Folder 40-42)
  - Arieti, Silvano (*), 1940-1945 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Ashley-Montagu, M.F.
    See: box 35, folder 661
  - Atwater, William C. (*), 1930-1955 (Box 3, Folder 44-45)
  - Atwood, Mildred
    See: box 75, folders 1415-1419
  - Aulmann, Georg
    See: box 112, folder 2114
  - Avery, George T. (*), 1922-1936 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - "B" general, 1899-1965 (Box 3, Folder 47-51)
  - Bachman, George W.
    See: box 63, folders 1192-1194
  - Bacon, Paul V.
    See: box 155, folders 2429-2432
  - Baird, John W. (*), 1907-1921 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Baker, George P. (*), 1918-1948 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Baker, Harvey H.
    See: box 81, folders 1552-1554
  - Baldwin, Bird T. (*), 1905-1927 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Ball, Josephine (*), 1923-1945 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Barbour, Thomas (*), 1910-1938 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Barnard, Chester I. (*), 1946-1952 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Bauman, John A., 1926-1929 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Bauman, John E. (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Bayne-Jones, Stanhope (*), 1938-1946 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    See also: box 105, folders 1982-1984
  - Beach, Frank A. (*), 1942-1955, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Beers, Clifford W.
    See: box 81, folders 1555-1559
  - Bell, James Carleton (*), 1904-1926, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Benchley, Belle J. (*), 1957-1964 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    See also: box 66, folders 1241-1246 box 113, folders 2132-2135
  - Bentley, Madison (*), 1908-1949 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Berry, Charles Scott (*), 1907-1952 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Bierens de Haan, J.A. (*), 1927-1953 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Bingham, Harold C. (*), 1912-1931 (Box 4, Folder 66-71)
    See also: box 58, folders 1109-1110
  - Bingham, Harold C., 1932-1964 (Box 5, Folder 72-73)
  - Bingham, Millicent Todd (*), 1937-1968 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Bingham, Walter VanDyke (*), 1911-1952 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    See also: box 73, folder 1397 box 81, folder 1566 box 95, folder 1796
  - Blackfan, Kenneth D.
    See: box 61, folder 1153
  - Blair, W. Frank, 1952-1955 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Blair, W. Reid
    See: box 113, folder 2120
  - Blaisdell, R.E. (*), 1945 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Blake, Francis G. (*), 1935-1952 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    See also: box 105, folders 1982-1984 box 109, folders 2038-2039
  - Blakeslee, Albert F., 1932-1936 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - Blanshard, Brand, 1946-1965 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Blanshard, Paul (*), 1949-1951 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Bohn, Georges (*), 1906-1924 (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - Boring, Edwin G. (*), 1919-1943 June (Box 5, Folder 83-87)
    See also: box 57, folders 1077-1082 box 72, folders 1372-1373 box 72, folders 1374-1378 box 99, folders 1869-1870
  - Boring, Edwin G., 1943 July-1951 (Box 6, Folder 88-98)
  - Boring, Edwin G., 1952-1967 (Box 7, Folder 99-104)
  - Bott, E.A. (*), 1917-1929 (Box 7, Folder 105)
  - Boudreau, Frank G. (*), 1943 (Box 7, Folder 106)
  - Bowen, Lois
    See: box 77, folder 1464
  - Bowers, Marie, 1903-1904 (Box 7, Folder 107)
  - Bowles, Chester, 1946-1950 (Box 7, Folder 108)
  - Brandes, Gustav (*), 1930-1948 (Box 7, Folder 109)
  - Brashear, John A., 1911-1913 (Box 7, Folder 110)
  - Breed, Frederick S., 1908-1952 (Box 7, Folder 111-112)
  - Breitinger, E., 1951 (Box 7, Folder 113)
  - Brett, George P.
    See: box 62, folders 1168-1170
  - Bridges, James W. (*), 1914-1916, undated (Box 7, Folder 114)
  - Brigham, Carl C. (*), 1917-1937 (Box 7, Folder 115-116)
  - Bristol, Edward N.
    See: box 84, folders 1629-1631
  - Britt, Steurt Henderson (*), 1941-1956 (Box 8, Folder 117-118)
    See also: box 76, folders 1436-1438
  - Bronk, Detlev W. (*), 1942-1955 (Box 8, Folder 119)
  - Brotemarkle, Robert A., 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 120)
    See also: box 95, folder 1797
  - Brown, C. Emerson
    See: box 113, folders 2129-2130
  - Brown, Harold C., 1902-1904 (Box 8, Folder 121)
  - Brown, Warner, 1921-1951 (Box 8, Folder 122)